<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Home</title>
<link>https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Peter Amerkhanian&#39;s Blog</description>
<generator>quarto-1.5.57</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Arrest Trends in San Francisco, 2018-2024</title>
  <dc:creator>Peter Amerkhanian</dc:creator>
  <link>https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos/SF-Arrests/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ In this memo I analyze trends in arrest and citation activity <sup>1</sup> in San Francisco between 2018 and 2024. Arrest activity decreased during this period, marked by a steady decline before the pandemic, a sharp drop at the outset of the pandemic, and generally low arrest activity in the post-pandemic. In the post-pandemic, arrest levels for almost every class of crime were less than or equal to arrest levels in the pre-pandemic, except for drug sale arrests, which substantially increased. The vast majority of those increased drug sale arrests took place in the Tenderloin. Indeed, the Tenderloin was an exception to the trend of decreasing arrests in San Francisco – arrest activity in the district increased in the post-pandemic, with drug sale arrests driving the increase. ]]></description>
  <guid>https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos/SF-Arrests/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos/SF-Arrests/thumbnail.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="111" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Policy Responses to a Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
  <dc:creator>Peter Amerkhanian</dc:creator>
  <link>https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos/SIR/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ During the COVID-19 pandemic, policy makers around the world have developed a variety of tools for combating the virus: lockdowns and strategic re-openings, testing, contact-tracing, masking, and vaccination, to name a few <span class="citation" data-cites="brooks_hammer_2020">(Brooks 2020)</span>. In this memo, I will examine the effectiveness of lockdowns and vaccination specifically, with an eye towards how they might be used during future pandemics. I find that lockdowns are an effective pandemic response in so far as they considerably reduce infections. I also find that a vaccine that provides temporary immunity cannot effectively end a pandemic with only one vaccination campaign. During future pandemics, policy makers should be ready to institute lockdowns, especially early in the pandemic, and prepare the public for yearly vaccine boosters once a vaccine has been developed. ]]></description>
  <guid>https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos/SIR/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://peter-amerkhanian.com/memos/SIR/thumbnail.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="62" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
